彼得：机器人汽车即将到来。最近我们看到自动化水平提高了
Peter: Robotic cars are coming. We’ve seen increased levels of automation in recent times
在普通乘用车。我们已经看到过系统，如支持警报，自动停车和
in regular passenger cars. We’ve seen systems like backing alarms, automatic parking and
等等，自适应巡航控制。最近谷歌特别引人注目
so on, adaptive cruise control. Google particularly, recently, have got a really high profile in
这个空间，但我知道大多数主要汽车制造商都有项目在寻找
this space, but I know that most of the major auto manufacturers have got projects looking
在开发完全自动驾驶的汽车和大量的人数
at developing fully self-driving cars and the number that gets bandied around a lot
是这项技术将在2020年前上路。
is that this technology is going to be on the roads by the year 2020.
很多人担心围绕这个问题的法律问题。那如果有自驾车
Lots of people worry about the legal issues around this. That if there is a self-driving
汽车，如果它导致事故，它杀了一个人，谁的错？但你已经
car and if it causes an accident, it kills somebody, whose fault is that? But you’ve
得到了我想平衡与人类是可怕的司机的事实。一切
got to I guess balance that against the fact that human beings are terrible drivers. Every
一年，有一百万人遇难，也许还有一亿人受伤
year, a million people are killed, and maybe a hundred million people are injured on the
道路，由人类司机。所以，如果我们有机器人汽车，他们可能会造成一些伤害，
road, by human drivers. So if we had robot cars, and they perhaps do cause some injuries,
但也许是我们现在受伤的人数的百分之一，道德要说的是什么
but perhaps 100th of the number of injuries we have now, what does ethics have to say
关于那个？机器人汽车是偶然的，这是件好事还是坏事
about that? Is that a good thing or a bad thing that robot cars would be accidentally
杀人？没有那么多，但也许还有一些？
killing people? Not as many, but perhaps still some?
道格：超过50岁，我总是回顾过去，回答未来，我在想
Doug: Being over 50, I always look to the past to answer the future and I’m thinking
好吧，让我们想一想过去的汽车设计。所以你和我都成长了
all right, let’s think of the design of cars in the past. So you and I were raised
在没有安全带的时候。当我们还是孩子的时候，我们都会跳到后面
at the time when there were no seatbelts. When we were kids, we all jump in the back
座位上，我们有五个人，我们就像仓鼠或兔子一样回到那里。我们有一个1964年
seat, there were five of us and we’re back there like hamsters or rabbits. We had a 1964
克莱斯勒萨拉托加。这些车的设计完全不是为了安全。
Chrysler Saratoga. The cars were designed not for safety at all.
它们的设计看起来很好......
They were designed to look good…
彼得：那时他们做了。
Peter: And they did at that time.
道格：是的，他们很精彩。而且它们的设计目标很快。我们有383V8和它
Doug: Yeah, and they were wonderful. And they’re designed to go fast. We had a 383 V8 and it
飞走了。那些日子里的心态并不是因为油耗
just flew. The mindset in those days was not around efficiency because fuel consumption
不是问题，因为石油很便宜。安全车不是为安全而设计的。
wasn’t an issue because the oil was cheap. Safety- cars weren’t designed for safety.
在那些日子里你遇到了一个意外，因为事实并非存在，所以你在车里乱成一团
You got into an accident in those days, you were scrambled inside the car because it wasn’t
设计友好。梅赛德斯-奔驰，沃尔沃，你知道这个故事。汽车开始设计
design friendly. Mercedes-Benz, Volvo, you know the story. Automobile started to design
围绕安全进入后期的60年代和70年代。这成了一个重大问题。引擎
around safety into the later ‘60s and into the ‘70s. It became a major issue. Engines
被设计为下拉，他们有安全带......
were designed to drop-down, they had seatbelts…
彼得：安全气囊......
Peter: Airbags…
道格：安全气囊出现然后刹车。随着安全成为一个标准，一切都改变了。
Doug: Airbags came along and then the brakes. It all changed as safety became a criteria.
汽车死亡是大多数第一世界国家的最大杀手。他们很大
Automobile deaths are the biggest killer in most first world countries. They are a big
毫无疑问，在暴力死亡方面，毫无疑问。
killer, there’s no doubt about it, in terms of violent death.
彼得：是的。
Peter: Yeah.
道格：所以，争论的焦点是，事实上，道德上是汽车制造
Doug: So the argument would be that, in fact, ethically are automobiles being manufactured
即使在今天，在最严格的安全感下保护人类生命？因为道德会
even today under the strictest sense of safety to preserve human life? Because ethics would
认为他们应该是，你应该设计这辆车，所以它就是
argue that they should be, that you should be designing this car, so that it’s the
在经济约束的范围内，最安全的汽车。所以，如果你从过去争论
safest car possible within sort of the economic constraints. So if you argue from the past
展望未来，看看这种机器人技术的构造，减少死亡，制造道路
to the future and look at this construct of robotics making less death, making the road
更安全，我认为它在使用机器人方面完全符合道德标准。
safer, I would argue that it’s completely ethically founded in terms of using robotics.
我完全没问题。
I have no problem with that at all.
彼得：所以从更好的意义上说，这太棒了。
Peter: So in a greater good sense, it’s fantastic.
道格：在目的论意义上，绝对是的，是的。
Doug: In a teleological sense, absolutely, yeah.
彼得：但是对于那个伴随着机器人车辆被杀的人来说，他们是
Peter: But for the individual whose partner was killed by a robotic vehicle, they’re
不会幸福。但我想如果他们被杀，他们就不会高兴
not going to be happy. But I guess they’re not going to be happy if they’re killed
通过人力驱动的车辆。
by a human-driven vehicle either.
道格：是的，再说一次，有什么区别？你是对的。它变成了一个案例
Doug: Yeah, so again, what’s the difference? You’re right. It becomes a case then of
法律，谁被起诉，如何。它是否会落在汽车制造商那里被起诉
law, who gets sued and how. Does it fall back onto the car manufacturer to be sued in that
案件而不是失去执照或被判入狱的个人的错误？
case rather than the fallibility of the individual who lose their license or get a jail term for causing that?
彼得：那么它成为一个法律问题而不再是道德问题？
Peter: So then it becomes a legal issue and no longer a moral issue?
道格：那是我的信念，是的。
Doug: That’s my belief, yes.
彼得：好的，所以这里更高或更道德的考虑是我们可以大大减少
Peter: Okay, so the higher or the moral consideration here is that we could dramatically reduce
在道路上遇害的人数，这是一件好事。
the number of people killed on the roads and that’s a good thing.
道格：当然，彼得。我相信。是啊。
Doug: Absolutely, Peter. I believe that. Yeah.